Good morning Church?
Thank you!
You may be seated, thank you!
Good morning once again?
I want to say good morning to the viewers all over the world!
I don't see myself leaving the word faith.
So let us begin where we stopped the last message.
Message Title: Talk on Faith!
Let's take our reading from the book of matthew - that is the first book of the new testament.
[MATTHEW 21:18]
'Jesus cursed a fig tree.'
18 Early in the morning, as Jesus was on his way back to the city, he was hungry.
"Seeing a fig tree by the road, he went up to it but found nothing on it except leaves.
Then he said to it, “May you never bear fruit again!”
Because he could not find anything on the tree, except leaves. Jesus said to the tree
“May you never bear fruit again!” Immediately the tree withered
Immediately the tree withered, when the disciples saw this,
they were amazed - surprised, what a manner of man is this?
"How did the fig tree wither so quickly?" They thought.
Jesus replied, "truly I tell you, if you have faith and do not doubt."
Not only can you do what was done to the fig tree
but also you can say to this mountain, "Go throw yourself into the sea and it will be done."
Think about that.
The last verse - Are you there?
That is verse 22
"If you believe you will receive whatever you ask in prayer" can that be true of you?
That is the question.
That is the question you need to ask. Ask your neighbor, can that be true of you?
The bible says,"If you believe you will receive whatever you ask in prayer" can that be true of you?
Because the word believe is not an application, but faith is an application.
Faith is a demonstration. Faith is a conviction. Faith is an application - you want to apply.
We can only apply all of God's blessing through faith.
If you say you believe, show me your faith.
"I believe" - show me your faith.
This is a question of the heart.
This is a question of what? - The heart.
Faith is of man's heart.
You may believe and not be able to express your faith.
Anyone can believe but not everyone can express their faith.
Many claim that they are believers, but they do not know how to believe and express their faith.
That is what is going on all over the world.
Everyone here say that they are believers, if they ask you, you say "I am are a believer."
But you do not know how to believe and express your faith!
Faith is an application. Faith is a demonstration. Faith is a conviction. Faith is practical.
That is the word practical - REALITY.
Yes, I can see this fruit - that is believe.
Yes, this is fruit in my hand - that is faith.
That is you and Jesus
I will demonstrate again, your relationship with Jesus; those who claim they are believers.
Yes, that is fruit, I believe it is fruit.
Yes!, it is fruit, this is fruit, it is fruit.
The word faith now,
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is faith now - you have faith to take it.
Without faith, you will continue to see the power, deliverance and all of God's blessings.
But you will not be able to apply them to yourself or make them manifest in you.
It is by faith we make all of God's blessings manifest in us.
By faith, we can apply all of God's blessings.
Faith is a question of the heart - whom we trust.
You can say, "I believe", but you believe not with your heart.
PROPHET T.B. JOSHUA - The Synagogue Church of All Nations.
For every matter, there are promises in the Bible - that God will do for us as long as we have faith.
Work without faith is dead, in the same way faith without work is dead.
What we do expresses what we believe.
The matter is quite simple - faith is expressed through work.
Faith work together with its work; by this faith is perfected, proved and completed.
If you say you believe, where is your faith?
Because faith is practical.
The belief in your heart is released by faith.
The belief in our heart can only be released by faith, if not your belief will remain dormant, inactive.
Ok, you can believe but it is dormant. If our belief remains dormant; what is dormant is what?
If you say you have money and you cannot spend it, do you have money?
Can you say you have money?
Because you need money it means you will be borrowing money.
When you have money and you cannot spend it, it means you will be borrowing money.
You will become a debtor.
So, the belief in our heart can only be released by faith.
When you don't have faith, the belief in your heart will remain dormant.
Are you a christian?
When there is no faith, the belief in your heart will remain dormant.
So how will you call Jesus, how will you talk to Jesus when the belief in your heart is dormant?
In Jesus name, you need faith; but there is no faith to release the belief.
You can only say amen, by faith you release the belief in your heart.
But it is not released.
"Thank you Jesus" you can only say this when faith releases the belief in your heart.
but the believe in your heart is dormant.
This is why I said, many claim to be believers but do not know how to believe and express their faith.
They claim to be believers but they do not know how to believe and express their faith.
You believe in God in a certain matter.
You should have the work of faith in that matter.
Tell your neighbor, if you believe in God in a certain matter, you should have the work of faith in that matter.
Faith without work is dead.
It means without the work of faith, that belief is dead.
And what is the work of faith? That is the question.
The work of faith can simply be defined in this way:
Absolute trust in God that he is now working out the answer.
That is the work of faith.
Tell your neighbor again, absolute trust in God that he is now working out the answer.
That is the work of faith!
If a man says he believes that God is working for him,
but he is busy making his own plans, worrying and distressed this is false faith.
I am about to go out and I realized that the cloud was dark and it is about to rain.
I now moved into my bedroom and begin to pray,
"Lord Jesus, Lord Jesus - I don't want this rain, I want to go to my work, help me stop this rain,Thank you Jesus!"
Then I say God has answered my prayer and I now move and
say to my family thank you I am going to work. It will not rain I have prayed to God.
God said to me it will not rain and at the same time I move towards an umbrella.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
and I put it inside my bag, and I say "Thank you Jesus."
and I am going to work. What does that umbrella mean?
In case of what? [It rains]
That has nullified my what? [My belief]
My belief.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That alone has nullified my belief.
Because if I actually believe in a certain matter, I must have the work of faith in that matter.
Carrying an umbrella is not the work of faith.
The work of faith is an absolute trust in Him that he is now working out the answer.
Is that not the life we live?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You pray over some trouble which arises in your life,
And later you find yourself full of anxiety and worries. As if you have never prayed before.
Prayer should be followed by an absolute trust in Him that he is now working out the answer.
Tell your neighbor - Prayer should be followed by an absolute trust in God
that he is now working out the answer.
Yes, after you finish praying what should follow is an absolute trust.
'Jesus, Jesus, thank you Lord, thank you Lord' What are you thanking him for
when you know he has not answered your prayer?
If you know you have not received, why are you saying thank you Jesus, because every prayer ends by what?
If you have not received teaching, the promise of the father - the Holy Spirit, in your spirit;
forcing yourself to do such acts indeed is a risk.
That is where your problem comes from - forcing yourself to do such acts indeed is a risk.
I believe that many of us have not received the promise of the father in our spirit.
You need to be grounded in the word of God.
Faith comes by hearing.
Since we have not heard and obeyed enough you cannot act in faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is where our problem comes from, you might have heard the word;
but you have not obeyed what you heard.
You hear it to teach it, you hear it to practice it but not hear it to live it.
Like the father of the demon possessed boy, he said, "I believe help my unbelief.
He was acting like us then.
He was acting like us, that is why he said to Jesus, "I believe, help my unbelief."
That kind of belief is like the belief we have today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is what the father of the demon possessed boy said to Jesus,
"I believe, help my unbelief," what kind of belief again?
If you believe and you are asking to help your unbelief,
it means the belief he had was the one of hearing the word of God to preach and to teach.
Not to live the Word.
If you hear the word of God and live it you will act in faith.
So, this is why we keep seeing the present darkness.
Physical eyes will always and continue to see the present darkness.
And the eyes of faith will always see the light.
The present darkness is the situation you are in now, your challenges are the present darkness.
This is the only thing you can see, you can't see beyond your situation.
That is why you lament, cry, doubt, become sober, anxious and worried
because all you can see is your present darkness.
You cannot see beyond your present darkness.
Assuming you have faith, you will be able to see the light.
Physical eyes can only see what? Present darkness! Tell your neighbor [...]
Our sight can only see the present darkness, but the eyes of faith can see the light.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And what is the present darkness? Your situation right now.
I call it present darkness because as soon as you change, you have faith,
you are converted through conversion - It's gone!
Because it is not something that is going to permanent.
Once you change, the situation changes.
That is why I call it present darkness.
Your sight can only see the present darkness.
And this is what you are seeing and is worrying you. You are thinking of this;
of hardship, limitation, poverty, sickness, infirmity, of the message you received,
nightmare, the phone call you received this is your present darkness you are battling with.
And as the result of your sight.
If I lived the way you have been living - you will not meet me here today.
Situations, challenges, what you people have done to me and what you people are thinking of doing to me,
this will not allow me to stand here to address you because I would be worried and thinking.
But I cannot see my present darkness at all, all I see is light.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And now that I am only seeing the light, it means that God is going to take care of any...
any darkness that appears to be darkness.
But you are seeing them and they are disturbing you,
you are being disturbed by your challenges and by all sorts of situation - you are worried.
Even when Jesus stands by you and you are seeing your present darkness - you will be worried.
I would like to know about it, what is going to happen next?
I don't know what will happen, will I overcome this situation?
How will I overcome the situation? The nightmare is too much, I am having pain,
my doctor says I should go and write my will, this is a deadly disease; what will I do about it?
This debt - how will I pay this debt? I don't know how to pay, there is no future, there is no hope.
Everything seems so rough.
Under that atmosphere you cannot have faith - you cannot express your faith, it is not possible.
You can only express your faith when you see the light,
but seeing the present darkness, it is difficult to express your faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Faith demands for a free spirit.
tell your neighbor!
But your spirit is not free; your spirit is in bondage, in prison.
Free spirit. Faith demands for a free spirit but your spirit is not free.
Your spirit is not free.
You need a free spirit to attract God.
So, this is why I said since you have not received the promise of the Father in your spirit.
Or you have not been grounded in the Word of God.
To be grounded in the Word of God is to have your spirit join himself with God's spirit.
That will now declare you a true born again. Not the kind of born again we talk about today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is a question of the heart: Whom do you trust?
This is why we need to struggle to believe.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And there is no need for us to struggle to believe.
You have to struggle, Jesus, Jesus, Jesus. You have to struggle to believe, and there is nothing like that.
It happens naturally instead you have to struggle to believe.
We don't need to struggle to believe.
This is the way with all kinds of faith.
It is when you have problems that you fast, you run here and there to the church, I mean...
many of us were supposed to be here a long time ago.
But because problems became overwhelming we run down to the church.
When the trouble has not become too much for you, you consult your elders,
'pharisees and sadducees for advice - where to go.
But when you now have so many problems and you know these problems may likely take your life,
you don't need to consult them, you go on your own. This is the way with all kinds of faith.
Anything that comes by force is not faith.
Faith is something that comes spontaneously - that is naturally. That is faith!
Who will open the door for the belief that you have?
The belief is inside the box, being locked.
Faith locked the belief and puts the key in the pocket.
For the belief to come out, faith needs to bring out the key and open the door for the belief to come out.
You have the belief but no faith. So your belief is dormant inside the box - it is inactive.
Christianity is not mere talk; we should put it into practice.
Its a thing of the heart, christianity lies in the heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
May God bless His Word.
Rise up for prayer!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We need to talk to our heart. This is a question of the heart, whom do you trust?
If I ask you, you will say you trust Jesus!
Will you allow your heart to talk instead of you talking.
If I ask, "Whom do you trust?" you will say "Jesus." Which is quite different from what your heart trusts.
This is a question of the heart, tell your neighbor. [This is a question of the heart.]
Christianity is a question of the heart.
When you are asked, "Who are you?" You say, "I am a christian".
Anybody can confess this and profess what is not in the heart.
It is a question of the heart, will you allow your heart to talk? Because faith is of man's heart.
Whom do you trust? Because faith is a trust. Tell your neighbor, [faith is a trust]
For you to struggle to believe is wrong. There is nothing like that, that struggle has ended over there!
You know the state where Peter's struggles ended.
When Peter saw Jesus on the sea, he said, "I want to come with you."
He started by putting his leg inside the water and was going inside the sea to meet Jesus.
As he was going, he was sinking, he was sinking; that is struggle.
He was sinking, he was sinking until the water level was here!
And Jesus said, "Come!"
He was still sinking and Jesus allowed him to struggle until the water level was here.
When the water level was above him and Jesus was only seeing his hands and fingers.
Jesus said, Yes! I can see your genuine willingness.
He said, "Come up!" [Clapping]
I know you need to struggle before Jesus notices you, and that struggle must be genuine.
You must struggle, your struggle will not impair you, but improve you!
So this is just the case.
Like I said, what you are seeing is present darkness.
And the moment you give all and surrender to Jesus you will begin to see the light.
Are you ready?
You just have to see beyond this present darkness.
Listen to the voice of God, someone is just changing your history. [AMEN!]
Let your story change!
Story of your health - change!
Story of your career - change!
Story of your business - change!
Story of your finances - change!
Story of your marriage - change!
Let your story change - In Jesus Name!
When your story changes, you will no longer see the present darkness!
This is the voice of God: Whatever is the story of your health - receive a new dream!
Breakthrough is a new dream.
Whatever is the story of your career - receive a new dream!
Prosperity is a new dream.
It's your new dream - receive a new dream!
Whatever is the story I don't want to know - up and down stories.
You know where you are supposed to be going by your effort.
You know where you are supposed to be going by your struggles.
You know where you are supposed to be. Let your story change!
Yes, going by your effort and struggles you know where you are supposed to be and where you belong.
You know!
Day and night effort to make it happen - It is the will of God to change your story!
Each time you sit down on your own, you keep asking yourself
How long shall we continue like this?
You have exhausted all your effort, tactics and strategies.
You thought when you've studied, thought when you've traveled to America, Europe all over the world,
you thought when you've had a good partner;
you would have what we call rest.
Yet, you are still struggling, at this moment you don't know what to do next.
This is why you run to God and say, "God I have exhausted all my strategies and tactics,
I have applied every intelligence and effort, I have done this and that I don't know what to do next."
"Rescue me lord!"
Rescue me lord and rewrite my history!
Rescue me lord and change my story!
Rescue my marriage, and change the history!
Rescue my business, and change the history!
Rescue my career, and change the history!
Rescue my finances, and change the history! In Jesus Christ Name!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Until you realize that, "No, I need someone wiser, smarter, cleverer." Who is Jesus!